In this clip I'm going to be doing a half arc up and over with the inflatable ball.
Now what we're going to do is extend one leg, keeping the other one with the knee bent.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to take our ball and we're going to bring it across the body and back.
Now I'm leaning at a slight angle.
If you have back issues you can sit up a little bit straighter, keep a nice long spine.
Reach across and I take it back.
You are going to try to keep those shoulders nice and relaxed, take it across and back.
Now if that is a little bit too easy for you, you can lift that leg slightly and just take it up and over and bring it back down in between, up and over.
Now for an increased challenge you can keep the leg elevated the whole time.
You are really going to feel a burn in the quad and you will also feel a little bit in the shoulder and the oblique.
Now this is the basic and your back is on an angle.
For more of a challenge, you can lift that leg up slightly and let it down, lift and lower, lift and lower or you can maintain and lower.
Now I would suggest doing 3 sets of 10 on each side.